[ EERIE MUSIC ]
[ RADIO STATIC ]
[ GIRL SCREAMING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ PANTING ]
[ GIRL SCREAMS ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ GIRL SCREAMING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ SOFTLY SOBBING ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ GIRL CRYING ]
He won 't get far .
GIRL : Help .
[ GIRL CRYING ]
[ GIRL SCREAMS ]
[ CAR ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ EERIE GUITAR MUSIC ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ RADIO STATIC ]
[ MUFFLED CHATTER ]
WOMAN : You still awake ?
[ GROANS ]
In the middle of a high speed chase . This better be important .
I just feel so good knowing you 're out there keeping us safe .
[ STATIC ]
And yours on your end ?
There 's a mess of chatter from state police
but it sounds like they got it under control .
Anyway , you 're about up so we 'll see you when you get in .
[ YAWNING ] Okay .
Hold on .
Looks like I got some kind of a
drunk teenager .
I don 't know .
Hey !
Hey , buddy , you know it 's a little cold to be crawling all the way home .
Stand by .
[ EXHALES ]
Big night , huh ?
[ LAUGHS ]
Holy shit .
Dispatch , where am I taking this guy ?
DISPATCH : Closest emergency services is still Marsh County .
Not sure what 's left of it after the fire . I think they 're moving , but they 're ...
- ... still listed on duty . - Okay , uh , how about Lakeland ?
It 's another twenty minutes at least . It 's your call .
Okay , you call ahead to Marsh . Let them know it 's me that 's bringing him in .
You call ahead .
[ SIRENS BLARING ]
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
Can I get some help here ?
Uh , Bev , I need hands up front . Bring a stretcher .
- Dispatch not call ahead ? - What ? We didn 't get a call .
- Bev ! Uh , wanna get his feet ? - Yup , I 'll get him .
- Okay . One , two , three . - One , two , three .
[ GRUNTS ]
- Alright . - [ MOANS ]
- Are you okay ? Can you hear me ? - What 's his story , Danny ?
- Uh , he 's bleeding , Bev . - We 're gonna take care of you .
Beverly , we gotta get him on a monitor and to see Dr. Powell . Let 's go .
[ CLATTER ]
Oh .
Hi .
TV : Coming back on the air after an interruption due to technical problems .
- What 's that about ? - Who knows .
They won 't let me do anything around here .
Oh , here 's a good one .
De-gloving .
- There 's a picture . - Ugh , Jesus .
You know , statistically , you 're more likely to die in a hospital than anywhere else .
- Cool . - Well , I could give you a catheter .
- That could be fun . - Are you even a nurse ?
I am in training .
That 's so cool . How about I 'm just gonna go to sleep , okay ?
I should go anyway .
I guess you won 't be needing this .
- Goodnight . - TV : All messed up .
Well , uh , in time , would you say you ought to be able to wrap ...
Well , you sure know how to make an entrance , Danny boy .
Yup .
- How you feeling , Maggie ? - I 've been having some pains .
Dr. Powell says the baby might be on it 's way .
Yup , she 's kicking up a storm in there that 's for sure . [ LAUGHS ]
Anyhow . I 'm just glad the doc stuck around .
That fire really did a number on this place .
And I can 't afford to be driving her into the city every time that kid gets fidgety .
- Give it a rest , Grandad . - [ LAUGHS ]
[ INDISTINCT CHATTER ]
- Let go of me ! Stop ! - WOMAN : Calm down . Calm down .
- Let go of me ! Stop ! - DOCTOR : One more second .
- Just one more second . - WOMAN : Easy . Breathe .
- Okay . - WOMAN : I 'm not gonna miss this .
- You gonna be able to handle him , Richard ? - Your friend here 's had quite a trauma .
Not that we have any ID bracelets left , but for the record his name is James .
- How bad is he ? - Well , he 's not been very cooperative .
The sedative will help us determine exactly what his condition is , but
our resources are limited here .
Everything 's been packed up for the move .
Looks like James here isn 't any stranger to needles . Where 'd you find this guy ?
He fucking bled on me .
Kim , I know getting transferred over here wasn 't your first choice
but you 're supposed to be boxing up files .
No , there are things called computers now .
[ SCOFFS ]
Can computers put files in boxes ?
Thank you !
[ SIGHS ]
So old school .
[ GROANS ]
You might need something a little stronger if you 're gonna get that stain out .
[ MUMBLES ]
Whatever , fuck .
- I can do my own laundry . - Well ! Look at you .
Brought you , uh ... coffee .
Nice . I was looking for that .
It 's mine now so don 't you get any ideas .
Right .
[ LAUGHS ]
You 're being friendly .
It 's good to see you .
Uh ... I 'm sorry . Am I interrupting something ?
- No , no . - No . No , no , no .
I 'm just gonna go make sure Bev hasn 't murdered my intern . I 'll see you .
[ SIGHS ]
Our guest is out for now .
He 's not badly hurt , but it will be a while before you can talk to him .
Fuck .
You should be gentle with Alison .
She 's still coming to terms with what happened .
- Yeah , okay . - As you know , Daniel
there 's nothing worse than losing a child .
When we lost Sarah , I was ... I was a mess .
It took a long time to come back from that .
- You just have to keep going . - Yeah .
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
[ CRYING ]
DANIEL : Beverly . Are you okay ?
Beverly . What ?
Jesus Christ .
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
What the fuck are you doing , Bev ? Beverly ?
- This isn 't my face . - What , Bev ?
No , no , don 't do that . Bev !
Put the scissors down . Look at me !
Bev , okay , stop !
It 's not me .
No , no , no , don 't do that . Bev .
- Can you help me ? - Bev , Bev , stop !
- No , no , no ! Beverly , stop ! - [ GUNSHOT ]
Oh , fuck .
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
ALISON : Daniel !
Daniel , what ?
- What did you do ? - What the fuck ?
- Kim . Kim , get out of here . - Cliff ?
- Kim , you don 't need to see this . - I was ... I was just ...
DANIEL : She came at me . She came at me . Okay . Alright .
- DOCTOR : Was that a gunshot ? - Uh ...
DOCTOR : My God , what happened ?
ALISON : Beverly , she attacked Daniel and the Robinson kid .
- Okay , I gotta call this in . I gotta call ... - Give yourself a second . Just calm ...
Tell them . I gotta ... just give me a second .
- Can you just call from the office ? - Give me a second .
[ PUKING ]
[ WATER RUNNING ]
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
[ ECHOING GROANS ]
[ GROANS ]
- How are you feeling ? - What ? I 'm fine .
- Shh . - I 'm okay .
Take it easy , Daniel . It looks like you might have had a seizure .
No , no , no , no . If you 're feeling dizzy , Daniel , you shouldn 't try to get up .
- DANIEL : Okay . - Just sit down , okay ? Come on .
- I gotta call it in . - No , you need to take it easy .
There 's a state trooper already here .
What ? Oh , God , how long was I out for ?
Not long . Apparently , he was already on his way .
Something to do with that kid you brought in . It 's not important right now .
This trooper 's gonna wanna talk to you . We should see about moving you to a room .
No , no , no .
You just experienced an extremely traumatic event . Okay , look
you are stubborn like your father was now . You should take this very seriously .
I am , I am .
- I 'm good . - Alright .
Daniel .
Mitchell .
There you are .
So what happened ? They told me you found the two of them together .
Uh , yeah . He was dead when I arrived and , um
she came at me with a pair of scissors .
How did you get here so fast ?
- Your guy in the other room . - What about him ?
We got a major bloodbath about twenty miles north of here .
Looks like he tore the place up like a butcher shop .
Uh , yeah . We looked him over and most of the blood on his body was not his .
Well , he has a long list of drug related priors .
So I think he gave your nurse something .
I 've got him cuffed to the bed for the time being .
He 's been out cold .
Well , I 'm here now . I 'll sort it out .
I need to take your firearm .
Yeah .
You know , Carter , your dad was a stand up cop .
I wonder what he 'd think if he saw this shit show .
Okay , we need to make sure everybody 's accounted for . Who else is here ?
Uh , Doctor Powell and Kim .
Oh , and , um , Ben and Maggie . She 's pregnant .
- Christ , what a mess . - Hey , uh
do you mind if I call it in ?
Alright .
Thanks .
[ RADIO STATIC ]
I 'm not getting through in here . Are you copying , Mitchell ?
I 'm gonna try the car .
MAN : Copy .
[ KEYS JINGLING ]
Dispatch , this is Carter at Marsh County . Do you copy ?
[ RADIO STATIC ]
- I have a code three and I need assist . - [ RADIO STATIC ]
Fuck !
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Hi !
What the fuck are you doing ?
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
Shit , shit ! [ GROANING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
- Help ! - Daniel , Daniel , Daniel !
ALISON : Richard ! He 's losing a lot of blood .
- Keep pressure over the wound . - Daniel , it 's fine . Look at me .
Kim , I need you to bring me a sutra kit and 8mg ...
- Keep your eyes on me , you hear me ? - Did you hear what I said ?
- Kim ? Kim , what are you doing ? - Kim , did you hear me ?
For fuck 's sake , come here .
You 'll be alright , Daniel , you 'll be alright . Keep breathing .
Put both your hands here . Firm pressure . Don 't stop . You keep him awake .
- Keep your eyes on him . - Good boy , Daniel . Good boy !
Kim ! Don 't let him close his eyes .
- KIM : Hey ! Stay awake . - Stay awake , Daniel , stay awake .
KIM : Hey !
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
[ HEART BEATING ]
Daniel .
Daniel ?
I 've stopped the bleeding for now .
Oh , thank God .
[ MUMBLING ]
- We know . - Whoa , whoa , whoa .
Hey .
Okay , maybe don 't try to get up just yet .
- MAN : What happened out there ? - Just give him a second .
It looks like they 've got the place surrounded .
- They 're not trying to get in . - WOMAN : Who are they ?
DANIEL : I don 't know .
I wasn 't able to get through . You ?
No .
We should move everyone back inside . Who knows what they want .
DANIEL : No , maybe we can ... barricade the doors or , uh
you know , get out some other way .
[ MAN SCREAMING ]
- Shit . I forgot about him . - [ SCREAMING ]
- Do something ! - [ YELLING ]
Fucking shoot it !
- Oh , my God , please ! Do something ! - [ DEEP GROANS ]
Help me !
[ GUNFIRE ]
Oh , my God , fucking help me , goddammit !
Help me , help me !
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ DEEP GROANS ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ SHRIEKING ]
What is that ?
I think that was Beverly .
[ SHRIEKING ]
- Jesus , what the hell was that ? - We 're leaving . Now , now , now , now .
Hey , that 's not a good idea , Daniel .
Wait , wait , wait . What about those fucking lunatics out there ?
We got other things to worry about , believe me . Mitchell , Mitchell !
You and I , let 's go get the cars , okay ? Are you with me ?
- [ BANGING AT DOOR ] - [ SCREAMS ]
- MAN : What the hell was that ? - Make safe , back up .
- Stay away from the doors ! He 's got a gun . - Back , back , back .
Okay , make safe . Make safe .
- [ SCREAMING ] Okay , okay , drop it ! - [ SCREAMING ]
Whoa ! Okay , drop it ! Drop it !
- Fuck you . - Get the fuck back .
- Okay , put it down . - Stay calm , stay calm .
- Everybody , just stay calm ! - Stay the fuck away from me !
[ HEAVY BREATHING ]
- DOCTOR : Calm down ! - [ CLATTERING ]
DANIEL : Okay ! Put down the gun , it 's okay . Everybody just calm down .
- Calm down , you said ? No , no , no . - Richard , Richard , Richard .
- There 's no reason to involve her in this . - DANIEL : Richard .
It 's not gonna help you . Listen .
Just give me the knife and this will all be over .
- It isn 't gonna help you . - Richard , I don 't know what to fucking do !
Don 't worry , Maggie .
He 's not going to hurt you . Just let me have it .
- [ CHAOTIC YELLING ] - [ SCREAMS ]
- No ! - ALISON : Richard ! Kim , Kim !
I got him , I got him .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Kim .
[ NERVOUS CRYING ]
- Look at me , look at me , look at me . - We are not gonna die in this fucking place !
Nobody wants to be in here any longer than we have to . Believe me .
- He 's not going anywhere . - [ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
- Fucking idiot ! - [ CHAOTIC YELLING ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
- [ GUNSHOT ] - [ SLITHERING ]
- Alright . - What the fuck was that ?
Kim , sweetheart , you 're gonna be fine . You 're gonna be fine .
- Fuck 's sake , he stinks . - [ GURGLED YELLING ]
- DANIEL : Mitchell ! - [ GROANING ]
[ MUFFLED SCREAMS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Stay back !
[ BULLET SHELL DROPS ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ YELLING ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ PANTING ]
Oh , fuck .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
DANIEL : Get in the office . Get in the office now . Now , now !
- Get in the office . - Okay , go to the office !
- What the fuck was that ? - I 'm not gonna argue with you .
- You need to tell me what 's in there . - I don 't know what 's in there .
- But please , just go . - Watch the door .
- Okay . You hold on . Who are you ? - Get the fuck away from me .
Whoa , whoa , just slow down . Who are you ? Who are you ? Just tell us that .
- I want him . Alright ? - Okay , look .
Alright . I think we all agreed that we need to get the hell out of this building .
- These personal differences , they 're ... - Oh , Daniel !
ALISON : Stop .
No one is going anywhere .
- Okay , alright . - Okay .
We don 't know anything about this place .
If you let us here , we can trust them .
You don 't need to do this . You ...
- Stop ! - He can 't answer you .
Shaun !
See ? That 's what the last people he trusted did .
DANIEL : No , you 're making a mistake . You can trust us .
- I don 't think so . - [ CHAOTIC YELLING ]
Wait , wait ! Please , please ! Whoa , whoa , whoa .
Get your hands off me . [ PANTING ]
Are you okay ?
You calm down . Okay , we 're good .
You wanna go through all this again ?
I know you believe me when I tell you we don 't know what the fuck is going on .
There were things growing out of her . You saw it , you saw it . What was that ?
We could , uh , burn what 's left of the place . Take them all with it .
Okay , listen to me . We didn 't do anything to you .
I have a girl back there who 's about to give birth ...
- ... and I need to get her some place safe . - Are you fucking kidding ?
Have you had a look outside lady ? There 's nowhere to go .
You can hear those horns for miles . There is something calling them all here .
- Okay , what is that ? Who are they ? - How the fuck should I know ?
- Go ask them ! - It 's okay , it 's okay .
All I know is that that thing woke up once already
and I don 't wanna be around when it happens again .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Oh , there 's a problem . Maggie .
I didn 't know what to do .
Okay . Hey , sweetie .
Are we leaving ?
No , not just yet .
Would you put that out ?
Al .
- What , this ? - Yeah .
- Put it out . - Okay .
I think we all should just remain calm .
Bullshit . We should 've been out of here already .
- You people need to wake up . - Or what ?
You think you 'll stand a chance if there 's another one of those things out there ?
- Okay . Okay , okay . - Will you , huh ? Who 's gonna stop it ?
Grandpa ? The teenage fucking slut .
- Come on now ! - Whoa , whoa ! Come on .
- [ CRYING ] We 're gonna die . - No , we 're not gonna die . You 're gonna die .
I 'm not gonna let that happen .
Okay .
I don 't know what the fuck you think you 're trying to do . Okay ? Calm down .
- He 's upsetting her and that is not good . - I need you to stay calm .
Can you please tell me what is going on over there ?
Her contractions are spread out , but she 's having abdominal pain which is a bad sign .
DANIEL : I don 't know what that means . What does that mean ?
That means that we can 't move her . It can make things much worse .
Also the last thing I need is to be performing a cesarean in the middle of this
but I have nothing here to help her and if I don 't do anything the baby could die .
I need to go to the med supply room . So I 'll go .
DANIEL : Alone ? No , no , no , that 's out of the question .
ALISON : I 'm not asking . We need to handle this now .
DANIEL : Alright . Okay , look . We have no idea what is out there .
We have no way of defending ourselves .
Plus these two fucking psychos now think that we 're hostage .
I 'm doing this .
You 're not . You 're not . You 're not even ...
If this is because of the baby then you need to get a fucking mental check .
This is not about us .
That girl
if she suffers an abruption then her baby will die .
If I try to take it out of her
and I don 't use anesthetic then she could die of shock .
Daniel , look at me .
Okay , fine . Fuck it , fuck it . Uh ...
Okay , but you 're not going alone . You have to promise and wait for me , okay ?
- You promise ? - Okay .
Alright .
May I approach ?
The girl 's not doing well and neither is the baby
so we need to go
and get some things to help her .
What do you want from us ?
Well , I have a shotgun in my cruiser .
- I have ammunition . - [ LAUGHS ]
We just fought our way in here .
I 'm not gonna just stroll back out again .
Okay , but
as far as I can tell we 're all in the same boat .
You 've got a rifle without any bullets and a couple of fucking fire axes .
I just ... it 's close and we can do it fast .
[ SIGHS ]
Alright , but we 're not risking our lives for you .
We get that gun , it 's ours .
Oh , absolutely .
Abso-fucking-luteley .
Okay .
I thought you said it was close .
What the hell ?
It 's still out there .
Yeah , but what are they waiting for ?
Let 's just make this quick .
Shotgun 's locked on the front seat .
I gotta release it , but
you get all the ammo out of the trunk .
Don 't get any bright ideas .
Hey , hold up .
Goddammit .
GIRL : What if they don 't come back ?
Daniel knows what he 's doing .
It 's alright .
I shouldn 't even be here right now .
I should be at Lakeland turning over patients .
Fuck this place .
Well , you 're stuck with us now , Kim , so deal with it .
How you doing , honey ?
It hurts .
What 's gonna happen to my baby ?
Listen to me .
You and your baby are going to be fine .
You have my word .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Shit .
Fuck .
What the fuck are you doing in there ?
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ SCREECHING SOUND ]
DANIEL : What the fuck 's going on in there ?
- Ah , shit . - K , time 's up .
- That 's our cue to leave . - [ EERIE MUSIC ]
Come on , goddammit !
Fuck 's sake !
Fucking hurry up !
- Look out ! - [ GUNSHOT ]
I 'm keeping the fucking gun .
This place isn 't gonna keep anything out .
Oh , my God . Hey .
- Fuck . - What happened ?
- Here , here . - Where 's Allie ?
Well , she went to get some medicine for Maggie .
- Where ? - The med room .
Jesus Christ .
She said there wasn 't anything to worry about inside .
Are you guys in the same fucking building ?
Would you please wait here , look after them ?
Excuse me , sir , would you mind following me ? Thank you .
That kid will be fine .
He 's been through a lot worse . Those people killed his family .
- I barely got him out of there alive . - Yeah , what about you , man of mystery ?
Mind your own business . And by the way , pretty stupid to go running off by herself .
Okay , I 'm pretty certain you can beat the shit out of me , but I consider it
my special privilege to hate my wife now so if you could kindly shut the fuck up .
This is Mitchell 's gun .
Look .
What ?
[ PHONE RINGING ]
MAN : Hello , Daniel .
Who is this ?
You saw
something .
I felt it when you woke up .
But what was it ?
I can show you more if you 'd like .
Hi , Richard .
I 'm sure it 's hard for you to understand .
Beverly found it difficult as well
but I assure you
my intentions are altruistic .
Please
tell me what you 've done .
Richard .
Richard , tell me .
Tell me !
You 're trying so hard to follow in your father 's footsteps , Daniel .
Do you really wanna follow him where he 's gone ?
I understand how desperate loss can make you .
The night you brought Alison to me , the life inside her
desperately clawing to get out .
Losing my daughter changed me , but
but I 'm doing what I have to to make it right .
You 'll understand soon enough .
DANIEL : Just please , can you please tell me where Alison is ? Just ...
You tell me , goddammit . You tell me where she is .
Don 't worry , Daniel .
I 'm gonna help her .
I 'm gonna help all of you .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
This is crazy ! I don 't know what I 'm doing . You can 't just leave us .
Kim . We don 't have a choice . Alison 's the only one who knows how to look after Maggie .
Please , look . Just ... these still seem to work inside .
- No . - We 'll keep in touch just in case .
We 're not gonna be gone long , we 're not going far . Look .
It hurts . It hurts so bad .
I don 't know what half this stuff is !
- Please , please don 't ... - Listen to me . Listen to me , please .
We 're just gonna down there , I 'm gonna bring back Alison
and I need you to hold out until then , alright ?
What if something happens ? What if those people get in here ?
- What are we supposed to do ? - Those people are not trying to get in here .
Those people are trying to keep us from getting out .
Okay , that 's the best that I can do .
I hope you know how to use it .
And , uh
that 's there just in case .
You better know what you 're doing .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Okay , let 's go .
You think were just gonna go down there and that 'll be that ?
If you have something to say than say it , you smug fuck .
Do you know what 's down there ?
Nope .
But I know someone who might .
Hey . Hey , meth boy .
- Oh , shit . - Oh , good , you remember us .
It 's not my fault , okay ? You gotta believe me . I didn 't fucking do anything .
- Just save it . Save it ! - Please help me !
- These guys are gonna kill me ! - Hey !
You 're gonna wanna pay attention to my questions .
Please . No , wait , wait , wait ! Oh , God , please don 't !
- Alright , pick a finger . - Don 't do this .
- No , no , you didn 't ask me anything yet ! - I wanna make sure you know I 'm serious .
- I believe you , okay ? I fucking believe you . - Okay , okay , hey !
Do you know anything that will help keep us safe ? Anything at all .
Anything that will help us survive .
It 's the fucking doctor . It 's that fucking doctor .
Okay , fine , we know that already . We don 't have time for this .
- You know what ? Make it clean . - No , no , please . It is him .
It 's him and I killed him . I swear to God I did you a fucking favor .
- Yeah , well , he 's not dead anymore . - How is that possible ?
What ? Oh , God .
Oh , no , no ! [ DISTANT SCREAMING ]
- Look at me , look at me ! - Oh , God !
Stop ! Listen to me .
- How is he alive ? What is he ? - I don 't fucking know .
- Okay , take his hand off . - No , no , please , please !
I don 't know , I 'm serious . I met a girl on the road .
Fucking please , please , please . I met a girl on the road and she told me
she could help me score crystal so I followed her to this fucking pill house .
- Except it wasn 't a pill house . - What was it ? What was it ?
It was an old farm house in the middle of nowhere .
All of these fucking junkies .
It was a mess . It looked like they 'd been killing people for a while .
He gave us drugs .
He watched us have sex . And he called the place a church .
What you 're telling me that Richard was some kind of sex fiend , religious thing ?
My dad knew him for years , we all did . That 's bullshit .
They were dressed just like this .
There 's a bunch of people dressed like this , okay ?
And they did killings and sacrifices and they made us watch !
You 're talking devil worshiping ?
No . No , I don 't believe in the devil .
Okay , but I believe in this . They made people change .
I saw it . Thank you .
You 're coming with us . There 's no reason to thank us .
- What ? - Yeah .
You know what ? We 're gonna visit your friend in the basement .
No !
- Mhm . - Are you nuts ?
No , you 've seen he can do . Let 's just get out of here , okay ?
- Fuck this place . - Yeah ? Have a look . Go on .
- Be my guest . - No , this is suicide .
Oh , my God . No , you 're as crazy as they are .
MAN : Yeah , maybe .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Down here .
Looks like this place is gonna collapse .
WOMAN : Can you hear me okay ?
Loud and clear .
The stairwell to the basement is at the back of the building .
Roger that .
Got it .
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
Look . Someone 's been here .
Kim ! Where are we going ?
The door to the morgue should be right there in front of you .
I don 't see any door . Just a bunch of corridors .
- You sure this is the right place ? - He went down the wrong stairs .
There 's only one set of stairs . I know where they 're going .
Hello ?
Carter !
Better not be leading us into a trap .
[ RADIO STATIC ]
[ MUFFLED CHATTER ]
What 's going on ?
- Oh , you gotta be kidding me . - Did you find it ?
Is there some kind of sub-basement or ...
No , no , no , what are you talking about ?
- A staircase going down . - What ?
Carter , can you hear me ?
[ EERIE WINDS ]
We gotta go back .
I can 't ask you to follow me down here . You understand ?
KIM : Guys , what 's happening ?
Nothing . We 're
we 're gonna go down the stairs .
Hey , leading in with him . Hey , you get to go first .
- Yeah , right . - I 'm not asking .
Quiet .
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
RICHARD : Don 't bother . You won 't be able to move .
- Richard ? - Be patient .
- I 'm almost ready . - What ... what is this ?
I ... I saw you die .
I had no idea that it would feel like this .
The years I spent operating on people .
Opening them up and stitching them back together again .
It 's remarkable , the sensation it 's
not pain , more a sense of release .
- Why ... why are you ... - Be quiet , please .
This is uncharted territory .
The chance to study my own transformation .
I understand your hesitation , Alison
but let me ask you
all these years , haven 't you ever wished to save someone beyond saving ?
No matter what the costs ?
Well , losing Sarah destroyed me .
But it also compelled me to find a solution .
You 'd be surprised at the things you find
when you go looking .
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
It smells like a grave .
[ EMERGENCY FLARE SPARKS ]
I 've seen this place before .
This was all over the house we cleaned out .
He made us look at things . The worst things I 've ever seen .
We found rooms full of bodies in the basement of that place .
They had someone on a table like they were doing surgery down there .
- Half turned into one of those things . - No !
No , worse than that .
Like a nightmare .
[ PANTING ]
It isn 't real .
It 's not real .
It 's a rat 's maze .
- Carter ! - [ RADIO STATIC ]
Is he here ?
Hey ! Yeah .
He has took me here to ... baby .
I 'm right here , kiddo . It 's okay , it 's alright . You 're gonna be fine .
You 're lucky your grandpa cares about you so much .
My grandpa just yells at his TV and smokes .
[ SCREAMS ]
- KIM : Shit ! Shit , okay , okay ! Wait , wait . - Help her , help her . Help her , please .
- The paradigm , I think . - Alright .
Okay , Maggie , hold still for one second .
I got this . Okay . I 'm gonna give you something that 's really gonna help you .
It 's gonna feel really good . You 're doing real good .
It 's gonna be real painless . It 's gonna be okay in a second .
- Okay , okay . - Just give me a second . Okay , okay .
Okay , you gotta hold her still . You gotta hold her still .
Easy , once I get this in . Okay , ready ?
There you go .
- Yeah , yeah . - It 's okay .
There 's no problem . No problem .
[ EERIE MUSIC ]
Great .
I 'm not going in there . Fucking shoot me .
Hey .
This is it .
This is what ?
I appreciate your enthusiasm
but we need to think this through .
[ DOOR CREAKING ]
This is a mistake .
Come here , you little fuck .
RICHARD : Do you know where you go when you die ?
I do .
You travel on , reborn into something else
like a caterpillar becoming a moth .
Until now I 've only been able to track the moth in its cocoon .
The body has to adjust , of course . It adapts .
We weren 't built for this kind of thing .
I admit , early on I made mistakes .
Some of those earliest mistakes are still down here with us .
[ ECHOING SHOUTS ]
In fact , they caused the fire that destroyed this hospital .
You see
they want to die , but I won 't let them .
[ WOMAN SOBS ]
Don 't cry , Alison . I am going to help you .
This is an end to the cycle of life and death .
Do you really want this world ? This world that took your son from you ?
Do you know what happened that night to your unborn child ?
- No , please . - Umbilical cord became entangled .
Simple as that . Strange , isn 't it ?
The very lifeline between you and your child
constricting like a noose around his neck as he struggled to get out .
Tighter and tighter until finally it couldn 't struggle anymore .
Nature 's futility .
I can stop it .
This is the first real step .
The true resurrection .
I lost my daughter to the abyss ...
but tonight ...
- ... I am calling her back . - Richard .
Please .
Don 't do this .
But it 's already done .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ PANTING ]
You are so beautiful , Alison .
You will become something truly remarkable .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
This is a slaughter house .
[ GAGGING ]
- Get this off of me ! - Shut the fuck up !
I should 've killed you back at the house .
Get a hold of yourself .
[ BABY CRYING ]
[ GROWLING ]
- Is she alright ? - She feels hot .
Oh , God . [ SCREAMS ]
- Lord ! Do something ! - Oh , God , okay ! Okay .
[ MUMBLING ]
- Get a hold of yourself . - Fuck you .
Look around us , huh ? I told you . This was a mistake .
- He knows something . - [ GRUNTS ]
[ BABY CRYING ]
VOICE : We need you with us .
[ HIGH-PITCHED RINGING ]
He 's in his head ! He 's in his head !
[ PUNCHING ]
- Stop it ! - [ GRUNTS ]
[ WHISPERING ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ GROWLING ]
- We 're in hell . - [ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
- [ GUNSHOT ] - [ SCREAMS ]
You 've got to hold her still !
- It 's gonna be okay ! It 's gonna be okay ! - [ SOBBING ]
[ GLASS BREAKS ]
That 's the front entrance !
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
Where are you going ?
Wait , goddammit !
[ CRYING ]
- God , I can 't do it ! - You have to !
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
We 're gonna die !
[ SCREAMING ]
No ! No ! No ! No !
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ GROWLING ]
You do what you have to do ! I 'll keep those bastards out .
I can 't kill her .
You have to do this .
You are the only chance she has .
- No . - Please !
- Sorry , I can 't . - Please do this !
[ SCREAMS ] Oh , my God !
Why did you do that ?
It 's finally time .
How could you ?
Your baby .
Doctor Paul is a great man .
I 'm lucky to carry his child .
Nothing else matters now .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ SCREAMING ]
Don 't worry .
Everything is about to change .
Get the fuck away from me ! [ CRYING ]
[ PANTING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ WHISPERING ]
Just wait .
Just ... just wait .
What do ... what do we have to do ?
Just wait .
This is your fault .
This is your fault !
[ GRUNTS ]
I wasn 't there . You should 've protected them !
Mother wants us to stay .
I told you , look after them .
But you stayed here .
You should have protected them !
Stay here .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ GROANS ]
[ PANTING ]
I 'm sorry .
What is this ?
[ PANTING ]
Carter , Carter , Carter !
[ SPEAKER ECHOING ]
Carter , where are you ?
Shut the fuck up , shut the fuck up , shut the fuck up .
Shut up .
Fuck !
VOICE : Daniel ?
Daniel ?
- Alison . - Where are you ?
I 'm scared .
No , no , no , no . Alison , I 'm right here . I 'm right here . I 'm right here .
Look at me , it 's okay .
Oh , I can feel it coming .
Oh , wow .
Hold my hand .
I need you .
I 'm not gonna leave .
MAN : Daniel .
I know your secret .
I saw it in your face .
The night Alison lost your child .
I saw relief .
What have you done ?
I 've given her what she wanted .
She 's a mother .
Isn 't she beautiful ?
Daniel .
Stay .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Do you see , Daniel ?
Tell me what you see .
I see
a monster
that thinks he 's God .
I 'm disappointed .
Of all the things I 've shown you
and you still don 't understand .
No .
No , you 're right , I don 't .
I refuse to let death be the end .
I defy God .
There are things much older .
Older than time and they blessed me .
Well , congratulations .
I spent my life resisting death , but now I understand .
I must embrace it .
I 'll have my beautiful daughter back .
I just need one final thing .
Come , join me .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
The others have all gathered to witness my daughter 's rebirth .
My disciples
ready for their own transformation .
You 'll experience it yourself
but first
you have to die for me
like your father and son before you .
You 've done wonderfully , my dear .
Now watch .
You will be my audience .
Watch the abyss
open itself to me .
[ CHANTING ]
[ CRACKING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
Calvin , bless my baby .
Place my daughter into this vessel .
- [ SCREECHING ] - [ SCREAMS ]
Yes .
Give yourself to her .
[ PANTING ]
Let her come to be .
- [ SCREAMS ] - [ BABY CRYING ]
It 's her .
You see ?
[ GROWLING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
- Hey ! - [ GUNSHOT ]
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Look out !
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ GROANS ]
Do it !
Do it .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
We will all be saved .
Everything has led to this .
[ INAUDIBLE MUTTERING ]
[ CRASH ]
[ MUFFLED GROANS ]
I can see it all before me .
The infinite astro workings .
It 's beautiful .
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
Don 't fight it , Daniel .
I can give Alison to you .
That 's what you want , isn 't it ?
She 's waiting for you .
All you have to do is let go
and you can be together .
That 's a good boy .
This isn 't the end .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
DANIEL : Yes .
Yes .
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ GROANING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ GROWLING ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ PANTING ]
[ HYSTERICAL BREATHING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CRYING ]
Is it over ?
Is it over ? [ CRYING ]
[ DRAMATIC MUSIC ]
[ THUNDER CRACKING ]
[ FOLK MUSIC ]